Friends, in the previous video, we
saw how the general insurance industry is
growing, who is the leader, who is the
quality company, and the result that we came out from that is that
ICC Lombard is one
of the leading companies and a
quality company, so the latest result of this company has just been released for
quarter one of Financial Year 24, friends, we will
see the overall performance of ICC Lombard so far, how it has performed in the past,
what new inputs will we get from these quarter one results and what can
we expect in the future from these quarter one results,
friends,
ICC Lombard has been in collection for three years, it is
in collection, now will we see a rise, then
how much will we see, to know this thing,
friends, let us see the results of such films,
quarter bank, right, similarly,
friends, if you want to see the results of other companies from different industries, do
not forget to subscribe to the channel and press the plus icon, right,
so friends, on this site, we saw that
general insurance is a growing industry
where growth of up to 15% is visible and can be
good, and ETV is the top company,
right in leadership and and quality, now from this,
we have the results of GI here  So
friends, let's see this complete data
of farewells that I have given, whatever things
I have mentioned in it, friends, first of all,
I have given the important data of any company which we need for analysis,
like separate data of manufacturing company,
separate data of insurance, here
we have given the company's share holder fund, policy
holder fund, all these things, so you will be
able to get information from this, in the link of this, done right now
and before that, at the bottom, at the lowest,
we saw the performance of ICC Lombard till date,
so if the general
insurance industry is big, then how has ICC been,
now you can see, in 2003,
premiums worth 8 crores were collected,
profit ability friends, turnover of 33 crores got
converted into 6400 crores, the
company which used to make a profit of 30 crores got
converted into 300 crores,
if we look at this entire history, friends, there were
two instances when the company has also
posted losses, this thing should also not be forgotten, friends,
industrial loss is a potential in bad times,
but let me tell you that
in the industry, this was the time when your
maximum  The company used to think that
if any company was profitable, then
your friends, it was one of the first to make
profits. It was the
most aggressive, that is, it did the most business.
And that is why
friends, these people brought EPUP in advance.
Friends, it was an emerging sector. As the
company grows, its profitability will increase.
Now, in the coming time, you will see other companies as well.
But when EPUP came, it was 2018.
We saw that in the last 10 years, the
company had collected premiums ranging from Rs. 3000 to Rs. 12000 crores.
So, there was consistent premium
collection. You will not even
see a break in the premiums.
Apart from 2010, where the premiums had reduced,
otherwise there were high consistent premiums
which were increasing. Due to this growth,
friends, during EPPU, we thought that yes, we will
invest in premiums here.
Friends, along with increasing the premiums, these
companies are also maintained by their solvency.
Insurance companies are now big
investors. Around 80% of
their investments are invested in the closed market, due
to which  They should get consistent income and
friends, these people
also invest in equity which also gives them profit on their
investment. So it is a simple matter friends, a
company like ICC Lombard which was
charging consistent premiums, has achieved
consistent profitability, such a
company would be friends, friends the investment value is
also quite big,
today the investment book of this company is around 45000 friends,
3000 crores has been created, so friends, from where did they start getting income, they are
also getting income from investments, so
right, in reality, the profit that we are seeing now is
not just from business, in an
insurance company there are two incomes,
one is proper business profit and
second is investment profit, so here
we saw that at that
time their profit is also consistent, they made
loss twice but other companies were still in
loss, so they recommend, yes
latest co with ICC Lombard and they bill
expect,
just we saw the reserve, we were going to read their, then the
IPO of the company came and
if you look at the IPO of the IPO, the company had
consistent growth friends  Premium income has
reached approximately 22 thousand crores last year from 12000 crores, so we can see
friends, in these six years, friends, premium has
doubled,
from almost 800 crores to 1700 crores, friends,
profit has been made,
this is a company worth approximately 10000 crores,
friends, in the post IPO
we invested, you can see
their first year price of 8600 and this
price will double, now double means it is not a very good
thing, their performance inside was very good
because the two-three years in between were
very challenging for them, friends, during the time of
Covid, friends,
profitability had fallen due to high claim
ratio, apart from that,
after Covid went, profits should have been read, but later
in the closed market, we did not count down well,
our insurance companies are
big bidders of the closed market,
friends, if the last 2 years did not go well quickly, then it will
not be good for the closed market either, so the
interest rates kept increasing, so the old
closed ones do not have good memories,
they do well in the new closed ones, but
they  If you had already invested, the
returns would not have been good, so in the last two years
and not good, here equity and closed, so
what happened, friend, the investment income has gone down
and we have seen them perform inside,
now what about till now, if you look at their performance,
friends, the premium has been increasing since 12 in 15 years,
we have already seen the growth till 12-13,
they get profit because of their investment income, it is
not necessary that it is good for them,
equity is a little big, now this much will
increase,
your reserve will increase, margin will increase, if you see, in the
long term, their margins used to be up to six years,
in real sense, insurance
margins are not that much, friends, this may be for two-three years,
but their margins are so good for six years that
this is also because there is no investment
income, this is not real business income,
right real income, this gross premium income,
investment income benefits due to which
their margins improve, so if
we look at the group of last five years, friends, the
pot till 11 will be useful for us, apart from this, let's go for
10  Till 11 is not very attractive
but it
is consistently available
as you see the company growing well
friends your Tibetan count is going to
improve further I will
take license on this performing company our
estimate friends look at the near term growth
based on the stock data I can think
that I should expect long term growth till 13
I have taken a conservative approach premium should be increased by 13%
profit should be increased right then we will
get good growth but what is the situation right now
friends last year I have given the data from h1 here
h1 means quarter one quarter
both together the
growth was there friends but I
already told you that the growth of premium here was
completely covered by investment income
otherwise due to the investment income
not being good we
saw the heart of ICC lumber this year ended
last year then we
saw premium falling in the last order also the demand was less
in quarter four which I have given the
data here friends there was growth of only 60% seven
days ago which was not good so till
now the trade of ICC people was
not good for the flood friends
your premium was 20%  So 20% cross
premium income is very good friends,
investment income is also very good,
total income is more than 14 in which
investment income, premium income both are increased,
right,
paint cost is more than 15, right, which is
less than the income, if seen, but it is
bigger only till 12, so the
profit is not good, so the premium is so
big, but till now there was no profit,
friends, the premium on quarter must have given a little rate, so
whatever tax was there has been taken out
in the quarter, so the premium which is the biggest
thing has come back in the field,
right, but profit till 12, that is, it is
not so attractive, so we can find out where the profit
broke, friends,
in the major cost,
their biggest expense is the claim,
which I told you, during the time of Covid,
these clean ones
increased to 17, so the premium increased, the
plane increased from 17 taka, you will not say the whole thing, if it
increased only from Dasategar, it is not like that, then it will be a
big thing, but these two expenses are
their main expenses, friends, right, other
expenses  Which is not that big but it is very
big, date this commission can be seen now
friends up to 600 such friends
their commission is big in quarter one right it is
not like that, it will keep increasing regularly,
this thing happens in management tell me yes these are
big, we pull off this
friends friends 500 crores so friends friends the commission has come
because of this your profit has come down,
friends we have to understand this from here friends in
normal case you should have got commission of 80-90 crores
but instead of 1890 your
profit fell by 556 crores it did not
read as much as it should have otherwise it would have been a direct reflector in
profit so friends there was marking in profit your
tapping capacity increased so
overall we will say that this is a
good result in terms of demand this demand is big we should
also see which is the big this is the big demand friends
motor is their biggest business 47% turnover
comes from motor which is bigger than only three places
so their premiums are very good big but the
number one player is not only motor
[music] it
is very good it is big so this
demand for health will also benefit the health company
otherwise  If the profit of a proper health company like Star Health
decreased, then the second contributor overall
helped them in expanding the business, friends,
love is clear on this photo one result, the
premiums have come good, the introduction will
remain and friends, profit will shine, this
time there are losses because this is your commission
fund, from next time it will slowly come off, so
profitability should have improved,
my
current trade,
now I have kept hope here,
from 19th I will see the premium increase this year, from
inside there are still 9 months left,
we have estimated this for one cotton of this year, now
friends, growth can also come till 15th,
but a range will be known, now they will say that
this cannot happen, friends, we will say that an
extraordinary group of 30% will come, that
cannot happen, you will know a range in
near terms, so it is your wish, if the
entire management has said that they will improve, right now
if I am conservative and think about the entire margin,
you will see the profit falling this year
till 12th, right, there was a big Harda dal
premium, that has been removed, the premium will
remain good while remaining conservative
I am thinking that profits will fall right now, right now the
quarter 1 results will come to us and
inside will give us profit is equal, so it is
not that we will continue with this for the whole year,
we will add new inputs that we get on quarter 10, so
for now then
extremely full list on demand
profitability, note it so good, based on these data,
friends, I have expected this,
right this year there will be a decline in profit by 19% and by 2021, on
this base, friends, this time we will
reach a premium of ₹25000 crore,
friends, live time hi premium will get you searched,
if the margins fall, you will
see a profit of 1500 crore, but if they do not
fall, then there will be profit also in lifetime brother,
because the most important demand which is
pulling you up, now profit and EPF are
linked, so P of 31, sorry EPF of 31,
so I have taken fair valuation of 930 i.e.
1000,
consider the inputs,
this will also be in your mind, just now a
cyclone came, so this is also a big thing for
this company
We will see it crossing the landmark of 50 thousand crores, not in total income, right,
this will be a huge achievement for
Lombard. This was the case for Lombard. In this decade,
one of its general insurance
companies will reach 50,000 crores. Its profit will be around 4,000 crores. The
fair valuation will be 2,500 crores.
Right, and by 2035, we will
see it crossing a profit of 5,6 thousand crores. Yes, do you
understand? A business worth around 1 lakh crores, a
profit of 67,000 crores. Fair value of 4,200.
So friends, if the fair value is 4,000, then
it supports you. We can earn a
lot of 6,700 crores from it. So,
we can expect friends. If I get a
multi-year rally in a company like ICC Monday,
multi-year means today, where it will
go multi-year with its valuation, then
I would expect the company's profits to
grow, and we should see
much better growth than that. So,
expect multi-year growth. We can expect
consistent and growing growth depending on it. So, one should
invest in such a company. Now, you will
not just look at the price.  If it is not running then only
such companies will remain with you
friends, every company which is multi-dagar today has been lying like this at
some point or the other,
so this is not going negative at the right time,
friends how much is the train right now, it is
35, when the air and it happened, I had typed 35
and the BP is 35's EPF, friends so their
P is running,
on profit up to 12 it is 40, so yes, look,
I hope till 2 there is wage, it should be
kept in it,
due to valuations, you cannot send it to school,
see friends, by the way, I have
given some data here, what is the market share of one day,
your premium up to 10,
profit margin of Group Bisht up to 6, combination which is very
important, all this data management must have been
given, you should look at it along with it,
I come to the management discussion, see
what these people are talking about, let's talk about total income, let's
talk about premium inside,
total income is an additional benefit
which is going to be received from investment income, but in
real business this premium, so
how big the premium should be known, see
Their cross direct premium of 18.9%
is huge and the industry's 17.9% is huge, so
it is outperforming the industry.
3.8 has just come in quarter one, so it
is very good compared to last year's 104,
friends. The combined ratio should be 100, so it is
close to 100,
this is also excluding the impact of
cyclone. Friends, see how much loss they suffered in the cyclone. They suffered a
loss of Rs 35 crore. They
got 0.35 crore. Right, it is not like that. The cyclone is causing
huge losses. The combined
ratio is 100 and 2.9%. So, if we
look at the impact of cyclone, then your
comment ratio of 100-2.9% is relief, profit and all these
things. Anyway, we have discussed it.
Solved, it
is 2.53x. 2.50 against one x, which
is already more than 1.5, friends, it is good, there is no
tension.
They have given some important ration of these things, which
is important, gross return premium.  I told you how much came in. Well,
this is already known.
You already know this in cross premium.
Look at the trade of the combine ratio. It
might not have worked last year, how will it work? The
combine ratio had reached 100.9, so
this is not favourable right now. Meaning
[Music]
So majority of people are favourable.
As I told you, they expect
growth of 13-14 here. But
why friends, this data is very less. Like it is
written here that the
general insurance industry of India is significantly penetrated. It is very
underrated. You can see that
India's premium to GDP ratio is just
one.
2.6 lakh crore. We told you that the GDP is 272 lakh
crore, friends, it was around 1%.
Now this 1% is a big low. You
look at other countries, like China, it was once in the same situation. China
's growth was more than double ours.
Their premium to GDP ratio is 2.2%.
No, you had other developed economies like South
Korea, UK, Japan.  It is quite good till 2030, we will
not see this,
friends, can you expect a premium of 2.0 till 2030, so what does
2.0 mean, look at it
simply, there will be
only 2.6 lakh crore in GDP,
this thin crore is not like that, there was a lot of
growth till 11-10-11
but it will not be 5 lakh crore because
penetration is low, if
this penetration happens then on GDP of 2.5 lakh,
on premium of ₹2.5 lakh, on GDP of ₹5 lakh,
premium of ₹10 lakh crore will
increase the size, especially the
companies which are maintaining leadership will get a big
benefit, so
what is the density, density means
how much does an average Indian pay, you can see
22 thousand dollars friends, 22 thousand dollars means
premium of 2000 is not even there, so why is this
because our income is very low, right, now
look at the pay off here, as the data is given, these
people pay an average premium of 2 lakh, so they are
paying premium as much as our income, right, so if this is
going to increase, then this will also
increase your premium, that is, today if someone  A
person pays an average premium of 2000,
friends, in general insurance he
will automatically pay a premium for 10 years,
due to increasing income, so friends, this
is in front of you, friends,
we can add it near 1149, which means if there is
any decline, then do not worry,
many people say, then do a stop loss, there is no stop loss,
friends, add it in the long term because it is a good company,
your stop loss is being done, ICC Lombard
company has not done a stoppage that they are going to close the
business and run away, there will be good
growth, friends,
add it near 1149 and
I am on the target of 1775 for this year,
right for this year, so we will see that in the coming time
we will reach 1775, now when it rises, the
whole world will come to buy, they will say
this is going, this is going, buy, I fell asleep, I had to buy it
here only, otherwise I am
giving time to someone, still I am
not late for much, this is a quarterly chart, now you
can see how many quarters times, 1 2 3 4 5
quarters continued  After the lower low, the
previous quarter closed higher in the first quarter.
Real was getting
attracted towards 1775. See, right,
after the result, you will get direction. If
levels were coming, you could have taken it. Right now
this bike should not come towards the level. However,
you should not have that near you, otherwise it can happen that
you also get it at 11:50. But yes, now
it should get attracted towards the target.
Friends, I would expect a target of 2200 here in 2 years.
Right, leave all this. The dividend will be
consistent. We are not taking it for 2 years. The
company is going to remain stable. We are
expecting a premium of lakh crores by 2035.
So the growth is good. I have
told you a research method in detail.
Right, so disclosure, I have told you
friends, we are not a tip provider. We have come up with some results
based on data.
You may like these things or not, then you have the
right to take your own decision and
do tell me in the comments
which company you prefer in general insurance. Right, so
thank you. So, my dear friends, thank you.